Remember the "Personality".
牢记人格
No murder, O.K?
没有谋杀，好吗？
Let's pray.
让我们祈祷吧
- Dad? - Zuhal?
-爸爸？-祖哈尔？
- Did you know Mr.Tayfun? - Of Course I did.
-你认识泰丰先生吗？-我当然认识
All the way from Kambura.
在坎布拉时就认识他
Sorry for your loss.
节哀
Be brave son. You can't escape fate.
坚强起来孩子  没有人能逃过命运
What fate? They blew up the flower man.
什么命运？他们把花匠炸死了
As founders of the "Dog Killer" Fan Club we officially welcome you.
作为“狗杀手”粉丝俱乐部的创始人，我们正式欢迎你
If you don't make an arrest within a week, it's over.
如果一周之内抓不到他，那就结束了
The girl whom Tayyar raped...
被塔亚尔强奸的女孩
she is talking to me. Look what she's saying.
她在跟我说话  看看她说的
Help me Nevra.
救救我内芙拉
Up until now, I have been her voice.
直到现在，她一直在向我倾诉
All these murders are for her revenge.
所有这些谋杀都是为了报仇
If we find her we find this one too.
如果我们找到她，我们也找到这个凶手
We have to go to Kambura immediately.
我们必须立即去坎布拉
Ladies, anyone who was raped or sexually abused...
女士们，任何遭受过性虐待或强奸的人……
please call this number.
请打这个电话
What do you mean by "they gathered the women"?
“他们把女人们聚集起来”是什么意思？
She is trying to find the girl who was raped by Tayyar.
她试图找到被塔亚尔强奸的女孩
O.K, just stand by. I'll think of something.
好吧，你待命  我要想一想
They checked out the burned house.
他们检查了烧毁的房子
Find a bulldozer immediately.
马上找一台推土机
And knock it down.
把房子拆掉
- I don't recognize the number. - Go on, answer it.
-一个陌生号码 -快接
Hello?
喂？
Just tell me everything from the beginning.
从头说起  把一切都告诉我
It was an ordinary day. I had just finished my grocery shopping.
那是很平常的一天  我刚在杂货店买完东西
As I left the shop Tayyar appeared out of nowhere.
我离开商店时，塔亚尔突然出现
He grabbed me and...
他抓住了我……
you know, in the woods.
然后，在树林里……
She remembers everything.
她记得一切
Just call me if you need anything.
有什么需要就打给我
Thank you very much. You don't need to hang around.
非常感谢  你不必在这里等的
Firuz...
菲鲁兹
the less you know, the better you can sleep at night.
你知道得越少  晚上睡得越香
Then you won't have to call me...
那样的话你就不会打电话给我了
or say "leave me alone".
或者说“别管我”
Do you think Nevra was convinced?
你认为内芙拉被说服了吗？
Absolutely.
绝对的
She was about to start crying, thanks to my story-telling skill.
我讲故事的技巧很好，她都快要哭了
By the way, I talked to Cemil. He said you have the rest of my money.
顺便说一句，我跟塞米尔谈过  他说我的钱在你这里
Yes, that's right.
是的，在这
- S..it! - What is it?
-妈的！-什么？
So much for been convinced.
你还说服了呢
She is following us.
她在跟着我们
- Where? - Don't turn around.
-在哪里？-不要转身
What are we going to do now?
我们现在要做什么？
S..it!
妈的！
What am I going to do now?
我现在该怎么办？
What now?
现在怎么办？
Think. Where is your home?
想想你的家在哪里？
Think, think, think.
想，想，想
Where is your house?
你的房子在哪里？
No, it's not going to work.
不，这行不通
Mrs Feza!
费扎夫人！
Let's go.
我们走吧
Come on, get up. Let's go.
来吧，起来吧  我们走
Get up. I don't know where but we should go.
站起来，我不知道该去哪里，但我们该走了
Here you go.
干得好
My bag...
我的包……
anything else?
还有别的吗？
O.K, this way Mrs Feza. Here you go.
好的，走这边  是的
Is she still following you?
她还在跟着你吗？
Keep going Firuz.
不要停下 菲鲁兹
Don't get out the car until I think of something, O.K?
在我想到解决方案之前不要下车  明白吗？
Mrs Feza!
费扎夫人！
I've read thousands of novels and I decided to write one myself.
我读过数千本小说，所以我决定自己写一个
And you two f..cked it up.
但是你们两个都搞砸了
-Listen to me now. -I am listening Mr.Cemil.
-现在听我说  -我在听  塞米尔先生
- Can you hear me Yeliz? - Yes, I can.
-你能听到我说话吗？耶利兹  -是的，我可以
I made some calls. We'll change the story a little.
我打了几个电话  我们将改变这个故事
What I'm about to say, get it into your heads.
我要说的是，把它记在脑子里
Smallest mistake, you're done with.
哪怕犯一个小错误  你就完了
Hello?
喂？
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
Yeliz met with Firuz? There must be a mistake.
耶利兹与菲鲁兹见面？一定有什么误会吧
No mistake. They are right ahead of me.
没有误会  他们就在我前面
It is obvious that they know each other. He is driving her somewhere.
很明显，他们彼此认识  他现在正开车带她去什么地方
O.K. Hang on a minute. Just calm down.
好  等一下  冷静一下
Do you mean Yeliz was bulls... tting you last night?
你是说耶利兹昨晚在跟你扯淡吗？
And now, she is with Firuz, right?
现在，她和菲鲁兹在一起，对吗？
Yes, that's exactly so.
是的，就是这样
I have to talk to Firuz to find out what's been happening.
我必须和菲鲁兹谈谈这到底是怎么回事
Just hang up.
先挂了
Don't call him now Sefer. I have to see where they are headed.
现在别打给他  塞法  我必须看看他们要去哪里
Listen to me. No one knows Firuz better than I do.
听我说  没有人比我更了解菲鲁兹
If there is something iffy going on, either he won't answer...
如果有什么不愉快的事情，他也不会接
or give me a lot of crap.
也不会跟我说废话
I have to call Firuz to find out.
我必须打电话给菲鲁兹找出答案
- Hang on a minute. - What?
-等一下-什么？
Are you going to tell him that I've been following him?
你会告诉他我一直在跟着他吗？
If I know Firuz well enough, he already figured out that he's being followed.
以我对菲鲁兹的了解，他已经知道了自己在被跟踪
No, it is not here either.
不，也不在这里
I made a note of everything.
我记下了一切
Even, chucking the TV set out. But no address.
甚至记录了不喜欢电视机，但没有地址
I am so stupid.
我好笨
Poor Agah.
可怜的阿加
Not in the wallet either.
也不在钱包里
But it should be on the car's log book.
但这应该在汽车的日志上
Yes, it should be on the log book.
是的，应该在日志上
Calm down Agah.
冷静下来  阿加
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
Thank you.
谢谢
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
Mrs. Feza, I don't remember where I live.
费扎夫人，我不记得我住在哪里了
I don't remember my home.
我不记得我的家了
What the hell is going on?
这到底是怎么回事？
Keep doing whatever you've been doing.
继续做你一直在做的事
Excuse me?
什么？
Keep following me. I called Sefa. He is on his way.
继续跟着我  我叫了塞法  他在路上
We have to sit down and talk.
我们必须坐下来谈谈
Everything should be here.
应该都在这里
I make a note of everything in this black book.
我把所有笔记都记在这个黑本子里
It says here "Combination for the Flat No 8 is 1682".
上面写着：“ 8号公寓的密码组合是1682”
But what is Flat No:8?
但是什么是8号公寓？
Where the hell is it? How the hell do I know?
到底在哪里？我怎么知道？
Why didn't I write down the address instead of the combination?
我为什么不写下地址而写了密码组合呢？
Such an idiot!
我真是个白痴！
Unfortunately, this is the situation we are in right now.
很不幸，这就是我们现在的情况
I don't remember.
我不记得了
There must be a reason why I forgot.
一定是有原因的
I'll take you to seaside.
我带你去海边
I can play flamenco for you.
我可以为你演奏弗拉门戈舞
- Olé! - Yes, sure, Olé.
-奥莱！-是的，奥莱！
Remember when you asked me how the idea came up?
还记得你问我这个想法是怎么产生的吗？
When you said why should others decide who is to be killed?
当你说为什么其他人要决定别人的生死时？
Do you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because they've always been the ones to decide.
因为他们一直是决定的人
Come over here.
过来
Gerome painted this in 1872.
杰罗姆在1872年画了这幅画
What are those people doing?
那些人在做什么？
That's what the painting is called. "Pollice Verso".
那幅画叫做“ Pollice Verso”
It means "thumbs down".
意思是“拇指向下”
And who is it for?
那是给谁画的？
For the gladiator.
给角斗士
Why? So he can kill this man.
为什么？所以他可以杀了这个人
Actually, it is not clear which one means "death" in ancient Rome.
实际上，在古罗马尚不清楚哪一个意味着“死亡”
This, or this.
这个或这个
But Gerome thought this was the fitting one.
但是杰罗姆认为这是一个合适的选择
If you do this, the gladiator will kill.
如果这样做，角斗士就会杀人
And there would be death in the Arena.
竞技场中将会有人死亡
If you do this you save the man's life.
如果这样，你可以挽救人的性命
But one is not enough. The decision has to be unanimous.
但是一个人这样做还不够  决定必须是一致的
What I mean is, who will die or live has to be decided unanimously.
我的意思是，生或死必须共同决定
Unanimous decisions are always deemed legitimate.
一致的决定总是被认为是合法的
It will take the guilty conscience away.
它会带走内疚的良心
At the end of the day, you are inciting to a murder.
归根结底，这是煽动谋杀
It is a crime.
这是犯罪
But this way, everybody can point the finger at each other.
但是这样，每个人都可以互相指责
And the crime disappears.
罪行就消失了
What this painting tells us that...
这幅画告诉我们的是
if you want to commit a crime and not get blamed...
如果你想犯罪而不会受到指责
all you have to do is to build a crowd around you.
你所要做的就是在你周围建立一个群体
It is no longer a crime, if you commit it with a large enough crowd.
如果你在足够多的群体中进行犯罪，就不再是犯罪
And...
而且……
do these remind you anything?
这些会让你想到什么吗？
Well...
嗯……
you upload a video on YouTube.
你将视频上传到YouTube
What happens is that it is judged by people you don't even know.
发生的这些事情是由你甚至不认识的人来判断
Like...
喜欢
and dislike.
不喜欢
Life...
生
or death.
或死
As you can see, nothing has changed in 2 thousand years Süveyda.
如你所见，两千多年来，一切都没有改变  苏薇达
Only difference is that you can't do this anymore.
唯一的区别是你不能再做拇指向上或向下的动作
You have to click on the icons.
你必须点击图标
I thought of it when I saw the painting.
我看到画的时候就想到了
We have the gladiator, so let the crowd decide who'll die.
我们有角斗士，所以让人群决定谁会死
- Did you hear it? - What?
-听说了吗？-什么？
The three man who were killed?
被杀的三个人？
The ones with the word "personal" carved on their forehead?
额头刻有“个人”的三人？
They were on the list in our website.
他们在我们网站的名单上
- Are you serious? - Why don't you check it out?
-真的吗？-为什么不自己看一下？
Switch on the computer Süveyda.
打开电脑  苏薇达
I found out at school. They just told me.
我在学校知道的  他们刚刚告诉我
One of them was running a food kiosk or something.
其中一个人是经营食品亭还是什么的
He says "they are extorting money from me. I hope the "Dog Killer" kill them all".
他说：“他们勒索我的钱，我希望“狗杀手”能把他们都杀死”
They issued the names too Only a day before the murders.
就在谋杀的前一天  他们在网站上公布了姓名
And people went wild. Everybody is loading names on the list.
人们疯狂起来了  每个人都在列表上输入名字
You know what this means don't you?
你知道这意味着什么吗？
"Dog Killer" is following our website.
“狗杀手”正在关注我们的网站
Alright then. What were you doing there? How do you know this woman?
好吧，那你在做什么？你怎么认识这个女人？
No rush. There is a time for everything. Wait till Sefa gets here.
别着急  等塞法来了再说
Here he is.
他来了
What the hell do you think you're doing?
你以为你在做什么？
Put it this way, I have to do the s... itty work...
这样说吧   脏活必须由我来做
because you have been so f..cking useless.
因为你一点用都没有
- What are you talking about? - Murders are piling up every day.
-你在说什么？-谋杀案每天都在发生
And your brains are messed up with Kambura.
你们的大脑被坎布拉弄得一团糟
We are not getting anywhere.
我们一点头绪都没有
They are going mad in Ankara. And I have to take all the s... it.
安卡拉的人生气了  我必须要做点什么
Remember coming to the hospital yesterday?
还记得昨天去医院吗？
They called me straight after you left.
你离开后他们就来找我
- Who are "they"? - Ones at the top in Ankara.
-谁是“他们”？-安卡拉高层人士
They said "there is something iffy going on over there. Dig into it".
他们说“那边有点问题  跟进一下”
I said "you want me to investigate my partners"?
我说“你是要我调查我的同事吗？”
They said "exactly".
他们说“正是”
Yes sir.
长官好
- Does boss know about it? - They probably told him.
-老大知道吗？-他们可能和他说了
I'll go and talk to him anyway.
反正我也要去和他谈谈
I have been a superintendent for years. I am not going to spy on my team.
我已经担任主管多年了，我不会监视我的团队
They told Chief Tolga, gave him a week.
他们告诉托尔加检察官，给了他一周的时间
If he can't solve it they'll show him the door.
如果他解决不了，他们会让他滚蛋
Yes sir, I understand sir.
是的，长官，我知道
Yes, you've told me sir.
是的，你已经告诉我了
But I think it is unnecessary.
但我认为这是不必要的
No.
不是
Because I trust my team sir.
因为我相信我的团队  长官
O.K.
好
I understand.
我明白
So, what is it? Do they suspect us?
那是什么？他们怀疑我们吗？
Thanks.
谢谢
Don't pretend that you don't already know Sefa.
不要装傻了  Sefa
They are just pulling the wool over eyes.
他们是在欺骗我们
They will want to justify their action when the case blows bigger...
当案情恶化时，他们想要证明自己的行为是正确的
in couple of days.
在几天之内
They'll say "we investigated the cops."
他们会说：“我们调查了警察”
Everybody is trying to save their own a..ss.
每个人都在努力拯救自己
It is all about saving your skin.
都是为了保住官服
That's what it is.
就是这样
Nothing beats the seaside.
没什么比海边更好的了
Nothing can beat it.
没有了
It must've been 50 years since I last flew a kite.
自从我上一次在这里放风筝已经过去50年了
50 years at least.
至少50年
I have to run to fly it. But how can I run?
我必须奔跑才能飞起来  但是我怎么跑？
I'll be back in a minute. Wait here.
我很快就回来  等我一下
Let me ask you something?
让我问你一件事？
How did you figure it out?
你是如何知道的？
I mean, how did you figure out that I was going to meet the woman?
我的意思是，你如何得知我要去见那个女人？
I didn't figure out that you were going to meet.
我不知道你们会见面
I only figured out that she was lying.
我只知道她在撒谎
But everything she told me made sense.
但是她告诉我的一切都是有道理的
That's right, it all made sense.
是的，一切都说得通
Except one thing.
除了一件事
No man in Kambura would marry a non-virgin.
坎布拉没有任何一个男人会娶一个不是处女的老婆
It doesn't matter how much he loves her.
无论是否爱她
It is against Kambura's customs.
这违反了坎布拉的习俗
That's why, the woman in question either never got raped nor she is married.
这就是为什么这个女人既没有被强奸过也没有结过婚
But since we knew she was married, I decided to follow her...
但是因为我知道她已经结婚了，所以我决定跟随她……
to find out where she was going and who was forcing her to lie.
查清楚她要去哪里，谁在强迫她说谎
That's when you came into the scene.
那时候我就看到了你
You're doing good.
你做得很好
May be not so good.
可能不是很好
But you'll do it.
但是你会成功的
- I can't do it. - You can do it.
-我做不到-你可以的
I'll tell you what, let's try 10 more times and...
我告诉你，让我们再尝试10次，
we'll quit if it doesn't work out.
如果还是不行，我们就停下
Go on. This is the first. We start with the first one.
继续  这是第一次  我们从第一次开始
Mrs. Feza.
费扎夫人
Come on.
来吧
It's O.K.
没关系
Let's go for the second.
我们来尝试第二次
Come on son.
来吧孩子
Well done.
做得好
No, this way.
不  这边
Faster.
快点
Three.
第三次
For the forth time.
第四次
Lie? Why should I lie to you?
撒谎？我为什么要骗你
If you don't believe me ask my husband.
如果你不相信我  那你去问问我的丈夫
Ask him if I was virgin when we got married.
问他我结婚时是不是处女
It's O.K Nevra.
好了 内芙拉
That's enough. We'll drop you off wherever you want to go.
够了，我们会送你去你想去的地方
What sort of a woman are you, making me talk about such things?
你算什么女人  让我谈论这些事情？
How can you do this to your own kind? Have you got no feelings?
你怎么能对自己的同类做这种事情？你没有感情吗？
What did your mum used to say to you Yeliz?
你妈妈过去曾对你说过什么？
What do you mean? What's that got to do with anything?
那是什么意思？跟这有什么关系？
What did your mum used to say to you when you were little?
你妈妈小时候对你说了什么？
How was she threatening you?
她怎么威胁你？
Wasn't she saying "do you want to become a whore"?
她是不是在说“你想成为妓女”吗？
"You'll end up becoming a whore".
“你最终会变成妓女”
Isn't that what she was saying?
她没说过吗？
What's that got to do with anything?
那和这有什么关系？
That's what she used say, wasn't it?
她就是这么说的，不是吗？
Do you know why? Because your mum knew exactly what Kambura was like.
你知道为什么吗？因为你的妈妈明确的知道坎布拉是什么样子
You know too.
你也知道
If you are looking for a wrong doing, it is the Kambura itself.
如果你想知道到底是谁的错，那就是坎布拉本身
Look mister, it is flying.
先生你看，飞起来了
It may even be so that...
甚至可能是这样……
you're telling the truth Yeliz.
你说的是真相
You really have been raped.
你真的被强奸了
Yes, why not?
是的，为什么不是？
Yesterday you were talking about everything in detail.
昨天你在谈论细节的时候
But you avoided the subject of rape. Why?
你回避了强奸的问题，为什么？
Because you couldn't do it.
因为你做不到
You had the guts to lie to us.
你有胆量骗我们
But you never had the courage to tell what happened to you.
但是你从来没有勇气告诉你发生了什么
You really have been raped Yeliz.
你是真的被强奸了  耶利兹
Mrs Feza, it is flying.
费扎夫人  飞起来了
We finally did it. It's flying.
我们终于做到了
Mrs Feza!
费扎夫人！
It's flying.
飞起来了
And then, you married the man who raped you.
然后，你嫁给了强奸你的男人
Why? Because the place called Kambura never left you with another choice.
为什么？因为这个叫做坎布拉的地方给了你另一种选择
That's what happened, isn't it?
就是这样，不是吗？
Come on, say it. Isn't that what happened?
来，说吧  那不是真相吗？
That's enough Nevra. Leave the girl alone.
够了 内芙拉  别说了
Because you've got nothing to say.
因为你无话可说
It means that it's not Tayyar who did this to you.
这意味着塔亚尔没有对你做过任何事情
He might've done it to somebody else, but not to you.
他可能对别人做了，但不是对你
But why are you lying, blaming him?
但是你为什么说谎，把责任推给他？
Is that what you want to believe?
这就是你想要相信的吗?
Who do you think you're fooling? Yourself or us?
你认为自己是在欺骗谁？骗自己还是骗我们？
Do you think your husband will get away with it if you point the finger at Tayyar?
你认为如果你把矛头指向塔亚尔，你的丈夫会逃脱惩罚吗?
I'll tell you what, you can blame all the men in the world...
我告诉你，你可以责怪世界上所有的男人……
but it doesn't clear off your husband.
但这并不能给你丈夫脱罪
I am off to Kambura. Are you coming?
我要去坎布拉  你来吗？
Sure I am.
当然
You can tag along too, since your job is to spy on us.
你也可以跟踪我们，因为你的工作就是监视我们
Don't bother, we'll meet you there.
坎布拉见
It got stuck.
卡住了
The kite got stuck.
风筝被卡住了
Mrs Feza...
费扎夫人
the kite...
风筝
Mrs Feza!
费扎夫人
The kite got stuck.
风筝被卡住了
Poor Agah.
可怜的阿加
That's exactly what you'll become.
你就要变成这样了
Never mind.
无所谓了
- Hello Ate?. - Nevra, where are you?
-你好阿提斯  -内芙拉，你在哪里？
I am off to Kambura.
我要去坎布拉
I was about to ask you to come to Kambura.
我正想让你也一起来呢
Is that where you are?
你在那里吗？
I discovered this place when I first came to Istanbul.
我第一次来伊斯坦布尔时发现了这个地方
When I was a student.
那时我还是个学生
I became a regular customer.
就成为了这里的常客
Do you like it? Nice isn't it?
你喜欢吗？
Yes, it is nice but...
是的，很好，但是……
how about the guys?
这些人是干嘛的？
They are on duty.
他们在工作
I don't like going around in herds either.
我也不喜欢成群结队
But I am being stalked by a psychopath. You saw it.
但是我被一个精神病缠住了，你看到了
You even saw him better than me.
你甚至比我看的更清楚
What am I supposed to do?
我应该做些什么？
Change your routine until they arrest the man.
改变习惯，直到他们逮捕了那个凶手
I had a routine until that man began messing with my life.
在那个男人开始搅乱我的生活之前，我一直都是这样
If you ask me what paradise is like...
如果你问天堂是什么样的……
I'd say "it is a place where every day is the same".
我会说“是一个每天都一样的地方”
Where nothing changes, including me...
一切都没有改变，包括我
a place where everything runs smooth.
一切顺利的地方
As a matter of fact, I built such a place and lived there.
事实上，我建了这样一个地方并住在那里
Now, there is a devil in my paradise.
现在，有一个魔鬼在我的天堂
Do you want me to close down my paradise because of him?
你要我因为他而关闭我的天堂吗？
And now, there is an angel there too.
现在，那里也有天使
In this case...
在这种情况下
Mr Cemil...
塞米尔先生
is it coincidence that the devil and the angel made their way into your...
恶魔和天使同时闯入你的天堂
paradise simultaneously?
难道是巧合吗？
have invaded?
是受邀而来？
Or was it fate?
还是命运？
I don't know that much but I must've left the door open...
我不太了解，但我必须把门打开
allowing both the devil and the angel in.
让他们都进来
This is not the place.
不是这里
Why did I come here?
我为什么来这里？
This is the place...
这个地方……
where an old friend used to live. His name is Nazif.
曾经住着我的老朋友纳齐夫
Now he calls himself "Naz".
现在他自称“纳兹”
It's O.K I suppose. No harm in it.
没关系，我认为没关系
I once did something here.
我曾经在这里做过一些事
They say the killer always returns to the scene of murder.
他们说，凶手总是回到谋杀现场
So did I.
我也是
I was supposed to forget about it.
我本该忘记的这个的
Wait a minute, your daughter is not here, is she?
等一下，你女儿不在这里  对吧？
We can go to your place. There are no cameras there.
我们可以去你家了  那里没有监控
The house is empty.
房子是空的
I can play flamenco for you.
我可以为你演奏弗拉门戈舞
Olé!
奥莱！
Yes, sure. Olé.
是的，奥莱
- How did you find out? - I wanted to see the place.
-你怎么知道的？-我想看看这个地方
A man hung himself, causing havoc in the town.
一名男子上吊自杀，给镇子造成破坏
I came to check it out. And this is the situation.
我来看一看  然后就这样了
As you can see, the place has gone back in time.
如你所见，房子已经不复存在了
There is nothing left. They covered it with earth, buried it completely.
他们什么也没剩下  用泥土完全掩埋了
I wonder who did it?
我想知道是谁做的？
I found out that too.
那个我也知道了
Havran Holding.
哈夫兰控股
They bought the land from a farmer two years ago.
他们两年前从农民手里买了这块土地
Havran Holding.
哈夫兰控股
They have foundations, granting scholarship to children.
他们有基金会，为孩子们提供奖学金
Cemil Havran is the CEO.
塞米尔·哈夫兰是首席执行官
And he is from Kambura.
他来自坎布拉
Cemil.
塞米尔
Yes, we will build a hospital there. What is your name please?
是的，我们将在那里建立医院。请问你叫什么名字？
Nevra Elmas.
内芙拉·埃尔玛斯
Mrs Nesrin's daughter.
内斯林夫人的女儿
Of course I know her.
我当然认识她
Where from? Kambura of course.
怎么认识的？当然是在坎布拉认识的
Do you have any more questions Miss Nevra?
你还有其他疑问吗？
Yes, I have.
是的，我有
What made you knock this building down after all these years?
过了这么多年  是什么原因使你拆掉了这房子？
-Especially right after... -Yes. Right after a sad incident.
-尤其是在……-在那场悲剧之后
And I knew Ufuk very well.
我非常了解乌福克
Sad.
我很伤心
May he rest in peace.
愿他安息
Look Miss Nevra, you can be called a native of Kambura.
听着，内芙拉小姐，你也可以被称为坎布拉人
Kambura is a significant place for me.
坎布拉对我来说是重要的地方
A life has vanished there.
一条生命在那里结束了
We decided to do something that would pave way for other lives to flourish.
我们决定做一些事情，为其他生命的繁荣铺平道路
Do you understand?
你理解吗？
That's why we decided to build a hospital.
这就是为什么我们决定建一家医院
I tell you what we can do...
我告诉你我们能做什么
make an appointment with me...
找个时间见一面
we sit down and a have nice chat over a nice cup of coffee.
我们坐下来聊天愉快，喝杯咖啡
By the way, this is my private number.
顺便说一句，这是我的私人电话
You're with the police force.
你是警察
Therefore you had no problem of obtaining my number.
因此，你毫无疑问能够获得我的电话号码
But, don't call me on this number again.
但是，不要再给我打电话这个号码
In fact, it is better if you forget this number.
实际上，最好忘记这个号码
It is best if you delete it from your contacts list.
最好将其从联系人列表中删除
But if it's too much trouble for you, I get in touch with your bosses...
但如果你给我造成了太多麻烦，我会与你的老板联系
and they can do it for you.
他们可以帮你
Is it O.K?
好吗？
Give my regards to your mother.
代我向你母亲致意
Stupid girl.
愚蠢的女孩
She's gone into all that trouble to find your number...
她费了很大劲才找到你的电话号码
to talk about this.
就为了问这事情
Let's not say "stupid"...
我们不要说“愚蠢”
let's say "enthusiastic".
可以说“热情”
Young.
年轻
Never ran into a wall.
从来没碰过壁
They broke it again.
他们又把它弄坏了
They broke the lock Mrs Feza.
他们把门锁弄坏了  费扎夫人
It is O.K now.
现在可以了
The locksmith had said that they follow your moves.
锁匠曾说过他们会跟随你的行动
They broke in when they realized that the house was empty.
当他们知道到房子里面没人的时候，他们会闯进来
Isn't that right?
是不是？
I checked the place. Not much damage. I don't think they took anything.
我查过了没什么损害  我不认为他们拿走了任何东西
The bedroom is a little messy. But apart from that...!
但除此之外卧室有点凌乱……！
There is supposed to be a fish there. I wonder if it's still alive.
那里应该有一条鱼  我想知道它是否还活着
Did it have a name?
它有名字吗？
Did the fish have a name Mrs Feza?
鱼的名字叫菲扎太太吗？
What did you name it?
你给它起了什么名字？
What would I name it if it was me?
如果是我，我怎么称呼它？
Agah?
阿加？
Yes?
是？
You killed Mehmet.
你杀了穆罕默德
They say Mrs Feza was kidnapped.
他们说费扎夫人被绑架了
I reported it to the police. They are looking for her.
我已经报警了  警察在找她
I told them what happened to her husband.
我告诉警察她丈夫发生了什么
They say it probably has nothing to do with it.
他们说这可能与之无关
They know nothing. Cops are useless.
他们什么都不知道  警察真没用
Finally! I have been trying to get hold of you since morning.
终于接电话了！从早上以来我一直试图联系你
I know dad. I am sorry. It's been such a hectic day.
我知道爸爸  很抱歉  今天很忙
I am still busy. But you can talk to me if it's emergency.
我还是很忙  但如果有紧急情况你可以和我谈谈
Do you remember the judge, Mehmet Yurtgil?
你还记得法官穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔吗？
His wife Feza was staying here. They kidnapped her.
他的妻子费扎住在这里   有人绑架了她
Kidnapped? Who? When?
绑架了？什么时候？
This morning, during the stroll in the park.
今天早上，在公园散步时
They say she got lost. But I am sure she was kidnapped...
他们说她迷路了  但是我确定她是被绑架了
by her husband's killer.
被杀她丈夫的杀手
They reported it to the police. But the police is not doing anything.
他们向警察报告了，但是警察没有做任何事情
Why would they kidnap her? She was very ill.
他为什么要绑架她？她病得很重。
I think they kidnap her to stop her telling the story.
我认为他绑架她是为了让她闭嘴
She may reveal what she witnessed to.
她可能会透露自己目睹的事情
You can't trust human brain. You can never know how it works.
你不能相信人类的大脑  你永远不知道它是如何运作的
Would you take the risk if you were the murderer?
如果你是凶手，你会冒险吗？
Moreover, Mrs Feza had begun to talk recently.
而且，费扎夫人最近开始说话了
What was she saying?
她在说什么
She was reading poems?
她是在读诗吗？
I see.
我懂了
To the space?
去太空？
I've got it, dad. I'll take care of it.
我知道了，爸爸，我会处理的
Don't worry, I'll take care of it.
不用担心，我会处理的
What's going on? Who kidnapped who?
这是怎么回事？谁绑架了谁？
Feza Yurtgil, Mehmet Yurtgil's wife.
费扎·尤尔吉尔，穆罕默德·尤尔吉尔的妻子
She suffers from Alzheimer's Disease.
她患有阿尔茨海默氏病
She's gone missing in the park.
她在公园里失踪了
By the way, Naz?m Hikmet travelled to space but police didn't know about it.
另外，纳兹姆·希克梅特去了太空，但警方对此一无所知
Let's go.
我们走吧
Unfortunately, we are closed to the press.
但是，我们不接受媒体采访
He will find out anyway.
反正他会查出来的
The anonymous tipper among us will tell him everything.
我们中间的告密者会告诉他一切
Now or later, what is the difference?
现在或以后，有什么区别？
You are not the ones who should be ashamed.
你们不是应该感到羞耻的人
The ones who see you as an item to be bought and sold...
那些将你们视为商品的人
they are the ones who should be ashamed.
他们才是应该感到羞耻的人
What did they teach us?
他们教了我们什么？
Complete the opposite.
完成相反的
You've got raped because you've wagged your tail.
你被强奸了，因为你摇了摇尾巴
You got harassed on the street because you revealed your body too much.
你在街上受到骚扰，因为你的身体暴露得太多了
So many young girls walking bent-over in Kambura...
那么多年轻女孩在坎布拉弯着腰走路……
to hide their breasts from men.
为了向男人们隐藏她们的胸部
Are you aware of it?
你知道吗？
The hump on children's back...
儿童背上的驼??峰
is our fault.
是我们的错
Mebrule used to hold the cardigan against my back to measure it.
梅布鲁雷以前用开襟衫靠在我的背上进行测量。
I am taking over from she left off.
她去世后我接手了
I wish she was here so I could knit something for her.
我希望她还在，那样我可以为她编织一些东西
But it is too dark to see in here.
但是这里太黑了
I am sorry Mrs Feza. We are left in the dark.
抱歉，费扎太太  我们被困在黑暗中
But we had to do it to stop others seeing what's going on inside.
但是我们必须这样做，以防其他人看到里面发生了什么
The door can't be locked.
门不能锁
You can't even shut it properly, let alone locking it.
甚至都关不上，更不用说锁门了
Mr Münir used to hate the doors too.
穆尼尔曾经也很讨厌门
Mr Münir, my cat.
穆尼尔先生，我的猫
He hated closed doors.
他讨厌关门
He used to tap it with his paw, asking me to open it.
他曾经用爪子敲它，要我打开它
But he was so exhausted in his final days.
但是他在最后的日子非常疲惫
He was unable get up.
他无法起床
He was unable to get up to even ask for water.
他甚至无法起床  无法要水喝
And I never realized.
我从来没有意识到
So intriguing.
如此有趣
This...
这个
look.
看
Guide to Documentation Sorting.
文档分类指南
I have this book too.
我也有这本书
This man.
这个人
His name is Tayyar Kaymak.
他的名字叫塔亚尔·凯马克
He raped a girl in Kambura sometime between 10 and 15 years ago.
他在10到15年前在坎布拉强奸了一个女孩
We don't know how old she was at the time.
我们不知道她当时多大
But she is an adult woman now.
但是她现在是成年女性
Ladies, I am looking for this woman.
女士们，我在找这个女人
Please come forward if you know anything about this woman...
如果你对这个女人有任何线索，请挺身而出
about this incident or about Tayyar Kaymak.
无论是关于这个女人还是关于塔亚尔
Believe me, the smallest of information you provide will save a life.
相信我，你提供的信息将能够挽救生命
Please, come forward if you know anything.
拜托，如果你知道什么，请挺身而出
Don't hide it.
不要隐瞒
Don't hide it, so the woman wouldn't have to hide anymore.
不要隐瞒它，这样女人就不必再隐藏了
The book has it all.
这本书讲了一切
How to sort documentation.
如何分类文件
There are many ways.
有很多方法
One of them is...
其中之一是
by numbering each letter.
通过给每个字母编号
For example 1 for A, 2 for B, 3 for C and so on.
例如，A代表1，B代表2，C代表3，依此类推。
And then...
接着……
yes, I always sort my documents this way.
是的，我总是以这种方式对文件进行排序
I never forgot.
我从未忘记
When you see the number...
当你看到数字
1682.
Mrs Feza, 1682.
费扎夫人，1682
1 is A.
1是A
No, it said "1682 is the combination for the Flat No:8".
不，上面写着“ 1682是8号公寓的密码组合”
If there is No:8, 1682 refers to something else.
如果有8号公寓，则1682是指其他事情
So, it is not 1, It is 16.
所以不是1，而是16
If it's 16...
如果是16
A, B, C, ?, D, E...
A，B，C，?，D，E
M.
M
Mebrule.
梅布鲁雷
You can call me on this number anytime.
你可以随时拨打此电话
All I want is to find that woman.
我只想找到那个女人
If someone did that to me, ruining my dignity...
如果有人对我这样做，破坏我的尊严……
I would commit suicide.
我会自杀
What did you say?
你说什么？
Yes, you.
是的，就是你
I said nothing.
我什么都没说
Yes, you did. You said if it happened to you...
是的，你说如果这件事发生在你身上……
I said I would commit suicide. Wouldn't you?
我说过要自杀  不是吗？
A man rapes you and you carry on living?
一个男人强奸了你，你会继续生活吗？
Who can bear it?
谁能承受？
How can you face your loved ones?
你怎么能面对亲人？
How can you go back home, to your family?
你怎么能回家告诉你的亲人呢？
Mebrule Blocks.
梅布鲁雷区
I've got it Mrs Feza. Mebrule Blocks.
我知道了费扎夫人
Flat no: 8. But what is the "2" at the end?
8号公寓  但是最后的“ 2”是什么？
Mebrule Blocks, flat no: 8.
梅布鲁雷区  8号公寓
16, 8, 2, B.
16、8、2，B
Beyo?lu.
贝约鲁
Agah, Beyo?lu.
阿加·贝尤鲁
Mebrule Blocks, flat 8, Beyo?lu. I've got it.
梅布鲁雷区，第8单元公寓，贝尤鲁大楼  我知道了
Mrs Feza, I found the house.
费扎夫人，我找到了房子
I found the address. Get up.
我找到地址  起来吧
Get up, we are going home.
起来，我们要回家了
Mrs Feza, I've got it. Come on.
费扎太太，我知道了
Let's go back to the station. We'll check the archives.
我们回局里查档案
To look for what?
寻找什么？
Suicides committed in the last 15 years...
最近15年的自杀事件
and we'll go back 20 years if necessary.
如果需要的话，我们回溯20??年
Because the girl committed suicide.
因为那个女孩自杀了
The girl whom Tayyar raped committed suicide.
塔亚尔强奸的那个女孩自杀了
That's why we can't find her.
这就是为什么我们找不到她
Because she is no longer alive.
因为她已经死了
We've got the address. How could I not remember it?
我们有地址的  我怎么就不记得了？
Just a minute, let me put the book back in its place.
请等一下，让我将书本放回原处
Yes.
好了
Mrs Feza.
费扎夫人
Flamenco?
弗拉明戈？
- Olé. - Sure, Olé.
-奥莱-当然，奥莱
Well, well, well...
好吧好吧
the honourable D.A, I can see you're having a good time.
尊敬的检察官先生，我可以看到你玩的很愉快
I am sorry to interrupt but we have to talk.
很抱歉打扰，但我们不得不谈谈
How did you know I was here?
你怎么知道我在这里？
How did I know?
我怎么知道？
I have as many informants as officers in my team.
我的团队里有很多线人
They tell me everything.
他们告诉我一切
Where you go, what time you finish work.
你去哪里，什么时候完成工作
They tell me everything.
他们告诉我一切
What do you want?
你想要什么？
Now, the honourable D.A...
现在，尊敬的检察官
who has been messing with my case and why?
是谁一直在纠缠我的案子，为什么？
This is number one.
这是第一个问题
And the number two...
还有第二个……
who specifically reinstated the man to the case...
是谁特别指定菲鲁兹
whom I removed.
恢复到案件调查中
Who is running this case? What's going on?
谁在插手此案？怎么回事？
Look, a little advice from me...
听着，我给你一些建议
do you know the secret to move up in the ladder?
你知道升官的秘诀吗？
Not to ask questions.
不问问题
F... ck the ladder.
去尼玛的升官
I don't want to move up anywhere. How about that?
我一点都不想往上爬  行不行？
Not moving up means you are stuck where you are.
不往上爬意味着你会被困在原地
And that's where you'll be buried.
那就是你被埋葬的地方
Are you threatening me?
你在威胁我吗
No, just talking about a simple rule of management.
不，只是谈论管理的简单规则
Rule of management. I like that.
我喜欢这样的管理规则
For a moment, I thought you were threatening me.
有那么一瞬间，我以为你在威胁我
Because I am allergic to it. It gives me the itch.
因为我对威胁过敏所以很痒
When someone threatens me I threaten them back.
当有人威胁我时 我会威胁回去
Now, talking about threats...
现在，说到威胁……
does your beautiful and respected wife know what you are up to here?
你美丽而受人尊敬的妻子知道你在这里做什么吗？
You are a good man Tolga. You wouldn't do such a thing.
你是是个好人  托尔加  你不会做这样的事情
You haven't got the evil in you.
你内心没有邪恶
That's right. I haven't got the evil.
是的，我没有邪恶
But when I walk out that door anything can happen.
但是当我走出去那扇门  什么都有可能会发生
You never know what a man is capable of doing.
你永远不知道人有多大能耐
Mankind is an unpredictable species.
人类是不可预测的物种
I don't know who gave the orders.
我不知道是谁的命令
They called both from Ministry of Internal Affairs and Ministry of Justice.
他们分别联系了内政部和司法部
They told me what to do and I agreed.
他们告诉我该怎么做，我只是执行
I swear, I don't know who is pulling the strings.
我发誓，我不知道是谁在发号施令
You won't say anything to anyone, will you?
你不会对别人说什么，对吗？
Everybody has a soft belly.
每个人都有弱点
Being lured by temptations depends on the one's personality.
能否被诱惑吸引取决于一个人的人格
And that's your problem. It has nothing to do with me.
那是你的问题  与我无关
Have fun.
玩得开心
You are great Mrs Feza. You really are.
你跳得太好了  费扎夫人  真的太好了
You were great.
你很棒
Come on, let's not keep the children waiting.
来吧，不要让孩子们等着
Shall we go now?
我们现在可以走了吗？
O.K, one more.
好  再跳一首曲子
This is the last one.
这是最后一个
Just a minute. Let's do it properly.
等一下  让我们好好跳
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们……
greatest name of all times of flamenco dance.
弗拉门戈舞蹈史上最伟大的舞者
A unique talent...
一位特殊的天才……
Senora Feza.
塞诺拉·费萨
[Cause of Death: Suicide.
[死亡原因：自杀]
Mrs Feza?
费扎夫人？
What happened?
发生了什么？？
What happened? Are you alright?
怎么了？你还好吗？
Can you hear me?
你能听到我吗？
Mrs Feza?
费扎夫人？
Please, don't do this.
拜托不要这样
This can't be happening.
这不可能
Please.
不要啊
Can you hear me Mrs Feza?
你能听到我费扎夫人吗？
Please, don't. Don't do this.
拜托，不要这样
Please, no.
请不要
I was going to take you home.
我本打算要带你回家
I was going to cook for you.
我本打算要为你做饭
I was going to knit a jumper for you.
我本打算要为你编织一件毛衣
I was going to look after you.
我本打算要照顾你的
I was unable to look after Mebrule. But I was going to look after you.
我无法照顾梅布鲁雷，但是我要照顾你
I wasn't going to be like Mr Mehmet. I was never going to moan.
我不会像穆罕默德先生那样  我永远不会抱怨
I was going to look after you.
我本打算要照顾你的
I thought of everything.
我把一切都计划好了
I was going to introduce you to my daughter.
我本打算把你介绍给我的女儿
I was going to introduce you to my grandchild.
我本打算把你介绍给我的孙子
I was going to say "Look, this is Mrs Feza."
我要说：“看，这是费扎太太”
"She is a dear old friend of mine".
“她是我的亲爱的老朋友”
"She is not well". "She is staying in a nursing home".
“她不舒服”“她住在疗养院”
"But she is lonely and unhappy there". "From now on, she'll be staying with us."
“但是她在那里感到孤独和不快乐”“从现在开始，她将和我们住在一起”
"She'll be forever staying with us".
“她将永远和我们在一起”
Please, don't do this.
拜托不要这样
This can't be happening.
这不可能
Olé, Olé, Olé.
奥莱！奥莱！奥莱！
[Hi Deva, I am the "Dog Killer".
[嗨，德瓦，我是“狗杀手”]
[F... ck off!
[滚开！]
[You don't believe me.] [But this little gift may convince you.]
[你不相信我] [但是这个小礼物可能会说服你]
- Are you going out? - I'll be right back.
-你要出去吗？-我马上回来
Nevra!
内芙拉！
Wait!
等等！
Nevra!
内芙拉！
Are you alright?
你还好吗？
Reyhan.
雷汉
What?
什么？
Reyhan committed suicide.
雷汉自杀了
Who is Reyhan?
谁是雷汉？
Don't tell anybody, O.K?
不要告诉任何人，好吗？
You promised Nevra. Don't forget.
你向我保证   内芙拉  不要忘记
O.K, I won't forget.
好，我不会忘记